Guide to the Fanny Burney Papers, 1782-1840
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Fanny Burney Papers
1782-1840
Burney, Fanny, 1752-1840
0.01 cubic feet (10 items)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
One letter from Burney to Mrs. Walshingham (1786), 2 letters from Hannah More to Burney (1782, 1786), 6 letters to Burney from other women, and one letter from Burney’s niece to a family friend announcing the death of Burney (1840).
Biographical Note
Fanny Burney (Frances Burney D'Arblay) was an English novelist, playwright, diarist and letter writer. She is known for her novels, Evelina, Cecilia, Camilla and The Wanderer, as well as several published volumes of her journals and correspondence.
Scope and Content Note
One letter from Burney to Mrs. Walshingham (1786), 2 letters from Hannah More to Burney (1782, 1786), 6 letters to Burney from other women, and one letter from Burney’s niece to a family friend announcing the death of Burney (1840).
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
More, Hannah, 1745-1833
Subjects:
Women authors, English; Novelists, English--18th century--Correspondence
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, May 2009.
Custodial History
Part of a collection gathered by Paula Peyraud. The letter from Burney's niece to Mrs. Pierce was purchased at a Christie's sale in April 1981.
Acquisition Information
Purchased for Vassar College by Bart Auerbach from the auction of the Paula Peyraud Collection, 6 May 2009 (M2009-009).
Appraisal
Appraised for auction by Bloomsbury Auctions, 2009.
Other Finding Aids
Items in this collection are described in Bloomsbury Auctions' catalog of the Paula Peyraud Collection (lot nos. 197, 209, and 224).
Container List
- Fanny Burney to Mrs. Walsingham, 20 Jul 1786 (Folder 1)
- Mary Dickinson to Fanny Burney, 22 June 1786 (Folder 2)
- Mary Hamilton to Fanny Burney, 23 March 1785 (Folder 3)
- Mrs. Harcourt to Fanny Burney, 11 Apr n.y. (Folder 4)
- Hannah More to Fanny Burney, 1782 (Folder 5)
- Hannah More to Fanny Burney, 1786 (Folder 6)
- Mrs. North to Fanny Burney, n.d. (Folder 7)
- Miss Palmer to Fanny Burney, n.d. (Folder 8)
- Mrs. Raper to Fanny Burney, n.d. (Folder 9)
- Charlotte Burnett (Burney's niece) to Mrs. Pearce, 4 Feb 1840 (Folder 10)